BANK OF SPAIN
5 YEARS BEFORE D-DAY
Hello.
Good morning, miss.
I have an appointment
with Mr. Mario Urbaneja,
governor of the Bank of Spain.
Alfredo Kesmann,
from Rating Trust Corporation.
Take a seat.
You're very kind. Thank you.
-Excuse me, where are you going?
-Hello.
And you?
-Have we met before?
-I'm asking you where you're going.
I'm here to see the governor.
Where are you going? For a walk?
It's a beautiful day.
They'll have told you to wait there.
They'll come for you.
No one was coming,
so I came up. I know the way.
-Mr. Kesmann.
-That's me.
-Nice to meet you.
-How are you?
Sorry about the wait.
-He'll be right with you.
-Great.
-Come with me.
-Thank you.
-Have a good day.
-I'll come with you.
Please do.
Rest, dear.
You?
I'm in charge of intensive care.
Don't worry, I was a nurse.
I'm going to the bathroom,
but I'll be here.
Thank you.
Mutt.
I told you I was going to kill you.
Which way did he go?
Rio, which way did he go?
For fuck's sake.
Where did he go?
Up the stairs.
Stockholm, Denver, stay here.
Don't let him get near the door.
If the hostages escape, we're fucked.
-Understood.
-Let's go.
-Helsinki, Bogotá, come with me.
Everyone, stand the fuck up, now!
What's happening?
Nairobi. Something's wrong. Run!
Nairobi!
-Nairobi, hold on!
-Nairobi!
Nairobi!
Nairobi, hold on!
He tried to smother her.
Her pulse was 162 bpm.
-Nairobi.
Easy.
Easy, breathe.
-Breathe, Nairobi.
-Gandía is on the loose.
Bogotá!
You stay with Nairobi.
If he comes back in,
blow his brains out, understood?
Helsinki, go after him.
-Look after her.
-My friend...
From now on, the rules have changed.
Nobody gets up,
nobody moves, nobody eats
without direct fucking orders.
You're fucked, Denver.
Really fucked.
-I don't believe it.
-Did you say something?
Yes.
You're not invincible anymore.
No. You're not invincible.
They're not invincible!
Arturo, shut up!
Or what?
Or I'll empty the gun
into your fucking head.
-Things have changed around here.
-Yes.
We're here, and now we're the Resistance.
Amanda, Miguel, we're the Resistance, hey?
We're the Resistance. Resistance!
Resistance!
Resistance, my ass.
Everyone, on the fucking ground now!
That's right, Sergio.
We need to know
how the bodyguards will react.
How they react,
how long they'll take
to get the governor to safety,
how they'll spread out...
-It's all in the protocols.
-We have the protocols,
we have the theory,
but we could do with a bit of practice.
And how do you propose
we get that practice?
By creating a minor security crisis
and watching it from inside.
-You're going into the lion's den?
-And the lion will protect me.
Who will you impersonate?
They'll think he's a genius, a big name.
A risk analyst
from Rating Trust Corporation.
Before that, he was at Bacher & Bacher,
and at Standard and Risk before that.
We're going to steal the identity
of someone truly brilliant.
A Spanish guy who has been living
in New York for more than 20 years.
Alfredo Kesmann.
A real genius.
And we have a few great suggestions
for the country's economy.
-The governor will appreciate them.
-Right.
-May I sit down?
-Of course.
But you could also
remain standing for the governor.
-You're the governor's head of security?
-Affirmative.
In a way, you and I do the same thing.
We're both risk analysts.
-We're very similar, don't you think?
-No.
We're not at all alike.
I analyze risks to save lives.
You do it to make money.
It's not the same.
Yes, we're similar.
What's more,
you're very clearheaded and... observant.
What risks do you see
here and now in this office?
Just out of curiosity.
If I could see any risks in this room,
they would no longer exist.
Don't you think?
Mr. Kesmann.
-Good morning.
-How are you?
-Good, thank you.
-Shall we sit down?
Let's.
Would you like some coffee, sir?
A Ceylon tea
with cardamom would be great.
-If not, any black tea is fine. Thanks.
-Of course.
If I had a coffee now, I would go crazy.
You can start your statement. Go ahead.
Before I start,
I'd like to clarify something.
I don't know if it's important, but...
I've been thinking,
and I wanted to ask you something.
-Shoot.
-What's it like when you get home?
I mean, you get home from work,
after torturing a kid like Rio,
who you've had standing up
for days and days
in a cell that's smaller than a closet,
shitting and pissing himself.
And then you go back home, to Germán.
I don't get it.
You don't mind
being called a torturer in the press.
But Germán...
Germán is a good person.
What does he say when you get home?
Does he ask you,
"How was your day, darling?"
And you kiss him...
and you hug him.
What about him?
Does he kiss and hug you back?
Do you fuck?
I think you must make him sick.
The truth is, it has been two months
since Germán hugged me.
He doesn't hug me, or kiss me,
or make love to me.
Not since I had him cremated.
They covered him with a white sheet
and took him down to the hospital morgue,
and that's when the embraces stopped.
What are you talking about?
He's dead.
Cancer...
of the pancreas.
The kind where they give you two months,
and it is two months.
I put on weight, and he lost it.
I was pink, and he was yellow.
It consumed him.
Life grew in me.
Death grew in him.
That's cancer.
Do you know the last thing he said to me?
Can you believe his last words were...
"Turn on the news?"
I thought he was going to give me
one of those talks of his
because, as you know,
he was quite eloquent and so imaginative.
And he said, "Turn on the news."
He was high as a kite on morphine.
So I guess he just lost it.
Then he just died.
I'm really sorry.
-Alicia, let's go outside for a second.
-Yes, coming.
Antoñanzas, stay and watch Murillo.
Don't let anyone in.
For God's sake,
why didn't you say anything before?
What would I have gained? A bit of pity?
Oh, Alicia...
I'm sorry, but I don't think
you're up to leading this case.
I'll take this.
This too.
Easy.
Try and die quietly.
Helsinki!
Hold on! Bogotá!
Bogotá, come to the library!
Helsinki, hold on, please.
-Hold on. Bogotá.
-Go!
Bogotá! Hold on, please.
The library, Bogotá!
Bogotá, quickly!
Help me!
Hold on, Helsinki.
-Quick.
-Come on.
Hold on. Come on!
Hold on!
Cut the rope!
Come on! Cut the rope, dammit!
Hold on.
Gandía!
You son of a bitch!
Silence, for fuck's sake!
I said, nobody talk! Nobody talk!
Amanda.
-How are you feeling?
-Better.
-I feel a bit calmer now.
-Good.
If you want,
we can go back with the others.
There's no rush.
The main thing is for you to get well.
-OK.
-Let me take your pulse.
No, it's still really fast, Amanda.
This is a major anxiety attack.
Do you have fluttering in your chest?
-Well, a little bit.
-That's normal. It's one of the symptoms.
Luckily...
I got something for you.
Here.
This works wonders.
Take three.
-It's not too strong, is it?
-No. A bit stronger than valerian.
-Are you sure?
-I'm sure. I've taken four.
-OK.
-Go ahead.
One at a time.
-Thanks.
-It's OK.
Everyone, listen up, please.
Let's see.
Many of you didn't know my husband,
Germán.
But the colonel thinks this concerns you:
he's passed away.
Tamayo thinks I'm not up to this task.
But the truth is,
there's no one better than me for this.
No one.
Because I don't fucking want to go home.
Or open the fridge.
Or the mailbox...
in case I see his name.
Or the boxes of photos.
So, I'm like fucking Deep Blue,
calculating 200 million moves a minute
against the Professor.
That's what this heist needs.
And it's what I need.
Anyone got anything to say?
No?
Then let's all cheer up a bit.
Back to work.
Rio.
Why the hell didn't you shoot?
I don't know.
I froze.
-And why did you freeze, Rio?
-Because I'm not a fucking killer.
You don't need to be a killer.
I couldn't shoot him in the chest
and pretend nothing happened.
Then shoot his leg!
-I can't!
-Then shoot at the ceiling!
Or the floor!
Wherever it takes to keep him still!
I'm telling you, I couldn't. I froze!
He said he had a family.
He was unarmed. I couldn't.
Why couldn't you?
Tell us why.
He couldn't, because he is traumatized.
I told you, and you fucking ignored me.
And now, because of you,
Helsinki and Nairobi were nearly killed.
Denver, enough!
Rio raised the alarm.
Helsinki and Nairobi are alive.
That's what matters.
You know what matters more?
How did he get free?
-You took Gandía to the bathroom.
-Yes.
-Did you put the cuffs on right?
-Obviously.
"Obviously."
Then obviously,
something doesn't fucking add up.
Tokyo, how does
a guy who is handcuffed escape?
Any ideas, Nairobi?
Any ideas? What?
Nothing, right?
Something smells very fishy to me.
Are you saying I'm a traitor?
-I don't know. You tell me.
-No. You tell me.
It's our fault.
We shouldn't have left
the kid on guard with PTSD.
Rio is no traitor.
We have a more urgent problem.
Listen to me.
The biggest risk is Gandía making contact
with the outside...
and them launching a coordinated attack,
from inside and outside.
What's the plan?
He has to be killed.
Who?
That guy.
We are not murderers.
Then we'll be corpses.
We'll get rid of the bodyguards
during the first hour.
They'll be the ones
who leave with the state secrets.
Problem solved.
Get the fuck out!
That bastard won't go out
with the secrets.
Nobody move.
He won't follow orders.
And Santiago?
-Did he get out after raising hell?
-Yes.
-It looked like an accident.
-The blast was magnificent.
I've brought my agency's
latest reports on country risk.
But...
they don't come out until next month.
We're still working on them,
but these are practically final.
And not encouraging.
They'll damage the risk premium
on your public debt.
-Any suggestions?
-Officially, liquid assets in the bank,
anti-inflationary measures, the usual.
But if I may give you my opinion,
which won't appear in the report...
Gold.
-Excuse me?
-Increase your gold reserves.
It's the only safe-haven asset.
And bring it here...
to the vault in the Bank of Spain.
Only that will support you in the market.
Look...
what happened in 2008 was a joke.
The real debt crisis is coming.
Are you telling me...
to bet the entire national reserve...
on a single color?
No, I'm telling you
to bet on the winning horse: gold.
What's happening?
-Don't worry.
-Was that an explosion?
Security to the governor's office.
Exterior security, it's Gandía.
Activate protocol red. Close the building.
-Anything outside?
-I can't see anything.
Where was the blast?
In the basement, sir.
It may have been a gas pocket.
Copy that. Don't close anything.
We may need to evacuate.
Maximum security alert!
Everyone with their vests on!
Everyone!
They have military weapons in there.
I think he caresses them in the evenings,
longing to pull the trigger.
He was a green beret.
He's been on the job for three years.
He was the minister of the interior's
personal bodyguard before that.
He was deployed on special ops
in Iraq and Lebanon.
Those are just the official ones
because during the six years
he was in special ops,
there are no records of his movements.
That means...
clandestine operations, secret missions...
He's a killer, Sergio.
He's a killer.
-Have you found the gun rack?
-We can't find it.
We've looked everywhere,
but there's no sign of weapons.
I don't know about the guns,
but his cuffs were in the library.
The bastard escaped from them by himself.
Like a child at Disneyland.
We kill him, or he kills us.
I saw him too.
I could see right through him.
If he gets the chance,
it'll be like he's playing a shoot-'em-up.
Faced with the slightest risk,
act decisively.
In self-defense...
but without hesitation.
Because he won't hesitate.
He's an unscrupulous ex-combatant.
He's merciless.
And he's trying to kill you.
What about the command center?
I'll make sure their hands are tied
so they respect the truce.
And also...
I'll make them see
that we're better than ever.
Right.
You need to take long, deep breaths.
Very good. Tell me something you love.
The sea.
The sea is perfect for this exercise.
Close your eyes.
Good. Now, Amanda,
imagine it's a hot summer's day.
You're on the beach,
at the water's edge,
with the waves lapping at your feet.
-Can you feel it?
-Yes, I can.
Now we're floating
on an air mattress in the water.
The sea breeze...
on the shore.
And the smell of summer.
I'm getting sleepy.
Let the sound of the sea carry you away.
Let the sea rock you to sleep.
The sea...
Amanda...
Come.
If you're calling to negotiate, press one.
If you're calling to surrender, press two.
If you're calling to ask what I'm wearing,
press pound.
-I caught you at a good time.
-Yes.
It's a beautiful day.
I'm glad. I wasn't sure how
you'd take the news I'm about to give you.
I just sent an exclusive
to a national newspaper.
They'll call asking you to confirm
that there's a truce. I hope you do.
Why would I do that?
Because if you don't, I'll leak
that you pretended to kill Lisbon,
that she's been illegally held since then,
and you're refusing to take her to court.
Those are trifles.
I also have a recording
of the supposed execution.
Bastard.
I can also tell them you're negotiating
by threatening to arrest
her daughter and mother.
But between you and me...
you're too late for that.
Those three CNI agents
at Katipunan police HQ in Mindanao,
and the Spanish consul,
Mr. Leopoldo Gis Bornay,
arriving in Manila
to coordinate the operation...
Save the taxpayers' money,
and while you're at it,
-save yourselves the embarrassment.
-You love hearing yourself talk.
You're like a radio host.
Get to the point.
What do you want?
I need to be sure about the truce.
I have someone fighting for their life.
Your word isn't enough anymore.
Confirm it with the press.
And in order to prove your goodwill
and boost the morale of everyone inside,
including the hostages,
I'd like to ask for one more thing.
News of the truce
was all over the press in minutes.
The headline was good.
But the photo was better:
the police leaving us eight paellas,
14 loaves of bread
and two cases of wine.
It looked like the start of a party.
This smells so good.
But inside,
it felt like the buildup to a funeral.
What you don't see is usually
more important than what you do see.
And Gandía,
on the verge of screwing our lives up,
was invisible.
Stockholm and Rio swept the first floor.
There's no sign of him. Listen.
The basements are my blind spots.
Helsinki to the east basement,
you to the west.
Tokyo.
I've just lost
the cameras inside the bank. All of them.
You're on your own.
What we don't see affects our lives
much more than it seems.
Nurse.
Let's see how you're doing.
And to think I didn't trust you before.
Why not?
Because you're
from Palermo and Berlin's gang.
And because you act like an Iberian male.
Macho, but a big, strong fellow.
Built like a castle.
He's sensitive is what he is.
I'm going to give you a shot,
Nairobi, honey.
Another one?
-Can't you give her a break?
-They're antibiotics.
She's at risk of infection.
You're awesome, Paquita.
I told her to give me another shot.
Well, if it's on the patient's orders...
You know how I said...
I wouldn't touch you with a ten-foot pole?
I'm reconsidering.
That was a very clear
declaration of your intentions.
Am I wrong, Paquita?
When you said that...
ten-foot pole thing...
you already had me.
Now I can picture you...
all dressed in white.
"I do."
-Wait...
-The reception, the friends,
-the boozing--
-Don't get your hopes up.
You're not having your eighth kid with me.
What we don't see is also
what haunts us the most.
He's not here.
Because once the doubts start...
it's not easy to stop them.
Rio.
Why don't you have scars from the torture?
You haven't even lost weight.
How did Gandía break free?
Why are you asking me that?
Because you lied.
You didn't tell the Professor everything,
and he said to be precise.
Why did you only tell me?
Why?
Why me?
Because there's so much shit in my head,
I can't sleep.
I didn't want to remember it
or be pitied even more.
I didn't want to describe
how I cried hopelessly in that coffin
and that the only thing I wanted
was to be in my bedroom
and to hug my mother,
who I thought would never know
what happened to me
because she wouldn't have
a grave to visit.
-Rio--
-I cried so much
that I had spasms
and hit my head on the coffin lid.
Sand fell into my eyes,
-and I kept crying.
-Stop.
Is that it?
Is that what you wanted me to tell you?
Forgive me. I'm sorry.
It's OK.
I'm sorry.
Easy.
It's all right.
No, it's not.
Sorry. I'm scared.
I don't know what I'm saying.
I'll make you trust me.
Rio.
What are you gonna do?
I'm going to kill Gandía.
You look for what you don't see.
But sometimes, you forget
the invisible might be watching you.
And then you're in trouble.
Yeah, that's better. Right, babe?
Now we're all cheered up.
Look at those faces.
No one else is going to rebel now, babe.
How wonderful!
What an amazing transformation
with a simple paella and a beer.
A round of applause for the bank robbers.
Stop screwing around
and shut the fuck up, now!
You have to let me go.
I smashed his head in.
Leave me here, tied up,
and it'll be worse than murder.
Free me.
Why would he kill you now?
He didn't before.
Don't worry.
We're looking for him now.
Great. You're looking for him.
That's good to know. Very good.
And it's also good to know
that they put you in charge
of the kids in the nursery.
What a wise decision, huh?
Who made that decision?
She chose Rio.
She chose the IT genius
to go hunt the most dangerous
professional killer in all Spain.
That's brilliant.
A traumatized little boy
who can't even bring himself to shoot.
And he's hand in hand with your ex,
crying in corners around the bank.
What a beautiful story.
He'll kill them, one by one.
When are you going to understand
that Tokyo's in charge?
This isn't about operating on Nairobi.
This is about survival, brother.
-Come here, moron, come here.
-What is it? What do you want now?
Listen, I know you really love Tokyo.
You've been through a lot together.
But do you think
she's the leader we deserve right now?
With your hand on your heart...
do you trust Tokyo?
You have to free me, brother.
You know it's the right thing to do.
You have to take me upstairs.
You have to free me.
Come on. Hey.
Shut up!
Matías, you're in charge.
Almost.
Rio!
-Where are you going?
-To kill that son of a bitch.
Rio, stop. I said stop!
Sorry about before.
I've got a lot going on.
But let me be clear:
I know you're an honorable man.
I know you'd never betray us.
Let's get that bastard together. Let's go.
Hello, National Police.
This is César Gandía, head of security
for the governor of the Bank of Spain.
I'm calling
on a Ministry of the Interior secure line.
Can you see that?
-Yes, it's a line from the Bank of Spain.
-Yes.
Get me the command center
outside the bank.
Top priority.
-Hello?
-This is a top-priority call.
-This is César Gandía.
-Who?
The governor's head of security.
Let me speak to Colonel Tamayo.
Yes, of course. Colonel!
It's the governor's head of security.
-Clear the room.
-Clear the area, please.
Colonel Tamayo speaking.
Colonel, I managed to break free.
It's Gandía.
-Where are you calling from?
-From the panic room.
I can monitor all their movements
with the internal CCTV.
I've cut all external connections
so they can't see us from outside.
I'm awaiting your instructions.
For now, remain inactive.
We have a truce.
What truce, Colonel?
How long is the truce?
There are more than 24 hours left.
I can't get out of it.
It's in the news.
In 24 hours,
these bastards will be in Singapore.
Let's launch a coordinated attack.
We'll take them by surprise.
It'll be over in ten minutes.
My hands are tied.
The Presidency doesn't want
more battles in Madrid.
Sir, I've got automatic weapons,
grenades, everything.
I won't wait for them to escape.
I haven't signed any truce.
Do you understand what I'm saying?
Officially,
I can only command you to wait...
even if that's not
what I'd like you to do.
What does that mean?
Whatever you do
will be considered self-defense.
There will be no legal issues.
If you eliminate them all,
you'd be a hero to me,
to the investigators,
and to the government.
Copy that.
Good luck.
The most important moments
are when we realize there's no going back.
That you've crossed a line,
and there's no way back.
The point of no return.
Everything is about to change,
and you cling to the present...
as if you could stop the disaster.
How are you doing?
I guess it won't come as a surprise...
but we arrived in Mindanao,
and your mother and daughter
were no longer there. Ta-da!
I'd congratulate you... but you know what?
I won't.
Because Rio,
before he went into the bank,
gave up all the carriers.
He didn't tell the Professor.
I was listening.
How quickly do you think
he'll give me your mom and daughter?
-Professor.
-Yes, Antoñanzas?
I know I shouldn't tell you this, but...
But what?
There will be casualties,
Tamayo's orders.
-In cold blood. It's a crime.
-What's going on?
Gandía, the head of security,
called the tent.
-He has a panic room and military weapons.
-Where is the room?
I don't know, but it has cameras.
He can see everything.
Tokyo.
-Tokyo.
-Professor.
Listen to me.
Gandía is armed. He has a panic room.
-What?
-He has a panic room.
He's watching. He knows where you all are.
Get everyone together.
Tokyo?